迈克:哇,你们大家一定觉得关于内战的这堂课很有意思,并愿意再待5分钟.
Mike: Wow you guys must find this civil ore stuff pretty interesting to stay 5mins
late
泰耐科先生:我想我不是在这里做一些让你们觉得胡闹的事吧.
Mr.Tenneco: I believe I just did an involuntary fandangle.
迈克:哦,泰耐科先生,你找我.
Mike: Yea Mr.Tenneco how can I help you.
泰耐科先生:实际上,我是想找你父亲谈谈.
Mr.Tenneco: Actually I wanted to speak to your father.
迈克:对不起,我刚才只是想让同学们了解历史充满了惊人之举.
Mike: Sorry, I was just showing the class that history is full of surprises.
泰耐科先生:有创意.但我找遍了所有的地方也没找到你的父亲.
Mr.Tenneco: Originally, but anyways I can't seem to locate your father anywhere.
迈克:哦,对了,
Mike: Well he's with my mom they're in Washington,
他和我妈去华盛顿了.我妈要做一个关于消费者权益的学术报告.
my moms giving a speech on consumer rights.
泰耐科先生:哦,卢克布鲁沃尔出了点事.
Mr.Tenneco: oh, something has come up regarding Luke Broward.
迈克:生物学.
Mike: Anatomy.
泰耐科先生:哦.
Mr.Tenneco: oh.
迈克:我说,泰耐科先生,
Mike: Look Mr.Tenneco when it comes to Luke I'm pretty much second in
关于卢克的事,我有足够的发言权.你跟我说就可以了.
command so maybe I can help.
泰耐科先生:别告诉我 ,这是弹道物理学上的事.
Mr.Tenneco: Don't tell me.The physics of trajectory.
迈克:不.他们只是不喜欢你.卢克怎么了?
Mike: No.they just don't like you.What about Luke?
泰耐科先生:儿童福利局已经找到了卢克的生父乔治布鲁沃尔.
Mr.Tenneco: The bureau of child welfare has located Luke natural father
他到纽约来了.
George Bower he's come to New York.
迈克:真的?
Mike: Really?
泰耐科先生:他想要回自己的儿子.
Mr.Tenneco: And he wants he son back.
开萝尔:哦,看啊,又上演了.这是莎士比亚的作品,你会喜欢的.
Carol: Oh look here's a revival of Macbeth its Shakespeare you'll love it.
克莉丝:我情愿看这个.
Chrissy: I'd rather see this one .
开萝尔:哦,是,我不会带你去看这种血淋淋,令人作呕的电影的.
Carol: 'It's raining guts' I'm not going to take you to see some gory disgusting slasher movie.
克莉丝:不看这个那就看.
Chrissy: Is either that one or bambi does Dallas.
开萝尔:还是看吧.
Carol: Ok guts it is.
本:听好了,女士们,先生们.本·西沃已经进入这座大楼.
Ben: Yes Ladies and Gentlemen Ben Sever has entered the building,
是的,谢谢你们,把孩子藏好,把东西锁好.
yes thank you thank you hide the kids and lock up the goods.
迈克:嘿,太好了,你在家.嘿,听着,我有事跟你说,是关于卢克的.
Mike: Hey thank goodness your home, hey listen I need to talk to you about Luke.
本:什么事?
Ben: What?
迈克:关于卢克.
Mike: About Luke.
本:什么事?
Ben: What?
迈克:关于卢克.
Mike: About Luke.
卢克:什么事?我好像听到有人叫我的名字.
Luke: What?I thought I heard somebody call me.
迈克:不,我们在唱歌,"
Mike: No we were just singing 'look at me I'm a as helpless as a kitten
看着我,我就像一只树梢上的小猫无助…"唱啊,本.
up a tree' come on Ben.
卢克:好吧.
Luke: Ok.
迈克:本,听我说,卢克的父亲来了,他想把卢克要回去.
Mike: Ben listen to me Luke's father is in town and he wants him back.
本:你为什么不告诉他.
Ben: Why didn't you tell him?
迈克:本,
Mike: Ben I can't just tell him.
我不能就这么跟他说.我是说他父亲在两岁时就抛弃了他,
I mean the father leaves when he is two years old and doesn't show his
13年里杳无音讯.
face for 13 years,
只有知道他完全改过自新了,才能考虑把卢克交给他.
I'm not handing Luke over to this guy until I know he's absolutely perfect.
本:你最好给爸爸打电话.
Ben: You better call dad.
迈克:我已经试着打过了.那家饭店根本就没有叫西沃的人.
Mike: Don't you think I already tried that there is no one at the hotel
named Sever
那你就等他们回来再说.
Ben: Well then you'd just have to wait till they get back.
迈克:本,等他们回来就迟了.
Mike: Ben I can't wait till they get back,
卢克的生父随时都会出现,
his father can show up and take Luke away any second and I have no idea
把他抢走.而我却不知道怎么调查那个家伙.
how to find out anything about this guy.
本:我可以.卢克!
Ben: I do.Luke!
迈克:你干什么?怎么能去问他呢?对待这种事必须慎重起见.
Mike: What are you doing?You can't just ask him you have to be very suttle about these kind of things.
本:迈克想了解你爸爸所有的事.
Ben: Mike wants to know all about your dad.
卢克:我爸爸?
Luke: My dad.
本:没什么,他是你一个人的.
Ben: It's ok, he's all yours.
卢克:问他干什么?
Luke: What about my dad?
迈克:哦,你对他还有什么印象吗?
Mike: Well ah do you remember anything about him?
他怎么会呢?你说过他两岁的时候,他爸把就溜走了.
Ben: How could he, you just said the guy skipped out when he was two.
卢克:哦,我知道的不多.我只知道他在什么政府部门里工作.
Luke: Well I don't know much all I know is he was involved in some kind of government work.
本:真的?什么政府部门,中情局,联邦调查局还是美国地方检察院?
Ben: Really?Like what are we talking about here , C.I.A., F.B.I., U.S.D.A.?
迈克:对,你爸爸也许是个秘密检察官呢.
Mike: Yea, the man was an undercover meat inspector.
这些年你爸爸都没跟你联系过吗?
So your dad he never made contact with you after all these years?
卢克:哦,他也许是秘密特工,
Luke: Well he was some kind of secret agent he was hiding with some witness
从事隐蔽并保护人证这样的工作.
relocation thing,
他也一直在保护我和妈妈,
he was trying to protect mom and me but I know someday he'll come back
我想有一天他会来找我的.
for me.
本:也许比你想的还有早呢.
Ben: Maybe sooner than you think.
卢克:我们以后再谈这个吧.我正在看电影录像呢,
Luke: Could we talk about this later,
那个人徒步去了东京.
I'm in the middle of a Godzilla movie his got Tokyo between his toes.
迈克:本,我该怎么办呢,
Mike: Ben what am I going to do,
如果他发现自己的爸爸到了这里.
I mean if he finds out his dad is in town he going to go straight
卢克会直接去找他的,他崇拜爸爸.
to him he idolize him.
本:嘿,如果我的爸爸是个特工,我也会崇拜他的.
Ben: Hey if our dad was a secret agent I'd idolize him to.
迈克:滚出去,你这个重金属傻瓜.我知道一个人也可以对付这件事.
Mike: Get out of here you heavy metal door stop.I would see how I
can deal with this by myself
本,本,
Ben Ben would you play that someplace else I'm trying to make a phone
你能换个地方弹奏吗?我正在打电话呢.
call here.
本:你可以走开啊,笨蛋,
Ben: You move duff burger you're on a space phone,
你打的是无绳电话.妈妈和爸爸走了,我终于可以想多大声就多大声了.
mom and dad are gone and for once I could play as loud as I want.
迈克:你想大声,这就是大声.
Mike: You want loud, here is loud.
本:你弄坏我的扩大器了.
Ben: You killed my amp.
迈克:啊,嗨,请找一下乔治布鲁沃尔.
Mike: Ah hi may I speak with George Bower please.
杰森:我真希望你能今天能跟我一起去,麦琪.
Jason: I really wish you could come with me today Maggie I hate being
我讨厌这样,整个太太旅行团里只有我一个男人.
the only man on the wives tour.
麦琪:很抱歉,亲爱的,
Maggie: Well I'm sorry sweetie I've got meetings all morning and I give
我整个上午都有会,下午我还要发言.
my speech this afternoon.
杰森:我不知道还能不能忍受一天的时间就是购物和看时装表演.对了,
Jason: I don't know if I could stand another day of shopping and fashion
这对耳环白天戴太大了.
shows and by the way those earrings are way to large for day wear.
麦琪:我想你还再忍一忍吧,就陪那些太太们一天.
Maggie: Well I guess you would just have to bit the bullet and put in
对了,你们今天的日程怎么安排的?
another days with the ladies, speaking of which what's on the agenda?
杰森:主要活动是是参观白宫,中午在斯米斯索尼安饭店就餐,
Jason: Well highlights are the white house tour lunch at the Smithsonian
还有就是,噢,在"可爱女郎"大厦举行告别晚会.
and oh a complete makeover at lady be lovely.
麦琪:你还要求比这个精彩的安排吗?
Maggie: Who could ask for an evening more?
杰森:别逗我了,麦琪.要不是为了你,我才不这么丢尽脸面呢.
Jason: Don't mock me Maggie if this wasn't for you it would be down right humiliating.
麦琪:你现在知道陪配偶是多么难捱了.
Maggie: Well now you know how the other half lives,
我陪你参加那么多精神病学研究会还不是一样.
what about al those time I've gone with you to the psychiatric conventions.
杰森:你从没跟我说过你不愿意陪我参加妄想狂研讨会.
Jason: You never told me you didn't like the paranoids seminar.
麦琪:我害怕拒绝你.你为507号房间设置了电话留言."
Maggie: I was afraid to.You've reached the voicemail for room 507.
麦琪马龙正在参加会议;杰森西沃正在参加美容讲座".
Maggie Malone is in
a conference and Jason Seaver is in waterproof I like 7 hours
迈克:哦,求求你,求求你,可千万别是乔治.
Mike: Oh, please, please, please.Don't be George.
艾里斯:老实点,乔治.
Iris: Be right with you George.
迈克:你好,乔治.我的,我的,我的…
Mike: Excuse me George.My my my my...
乔治二:哇,大个子.这小子弄脏了你的衣服,该死的东西.
George2: Wow big guy we have to salt that puppy down before it stains,
艾里斯,再拿几张餐巾纸来.给我这位朋友再拿一份新鲜的波士顿奶油馅饼来.
Iris we need a couple of more napkins and ah make sure my compadre here gets a fresh slice of that Boston cream pie.
我讨厌波士顿.
George1: I hate Boston.
乔治二:好吧,兄弟,要是没什么的话.我们给你洗干净了,或者再买件新的换上.你先走,大个子.半夜我会赶上的…
George2: Ok partner we got you covered for dry cleaning or a new shirt if
the spirit moves you got to fly big buddy catch you later on a midnight
乔治一:噢,住嘴.
George1: ah shut up.
乔治二:10点见.
George2: Ten full.
哦,谢谢你,不过我还得跟那个人谈谈.
Mike: Oh thank you very much but I still have to talk to that guy.
乔治二:除非你想让他把你揍一顿.我才是你想找的乔治.
George2: Not unless you want a belly button on both sides I'm the George
你是迈克,是吗?
you want you're Mike right?
迈克:是的,你是乔治布鲁沃尔?
Mike: Yea you're George Bower.
乔治二:我就是着名的,受人尊敬的乔治,不信你去问那些在路上干活的人.
George2: Know and respected where ever hardworking men on the road stop to catch their breath and drink.
乔治一:我说住嘴.
George1: I said shut up.
乔治二:别理他,坐吧.
George2: Lock that coffee, sit down.
艾里斯:咖啡,昨天刚冲的,新鲜的.
Iris: Coffee made a fresh pot yesterday.
迈克:哦,不,谢谢了.
Mike: Ah no thanks.
乔治二:小乖乖,我从来没有见过这么一双让人停止呼吸的,
George2: Sweetie pie you have got the most set of breath taking gorgeous
柔嫩的小手.真漂亮.
pair of hands I've ever seen.
没把我儿子带来吗?你想先看看我怎么样.
You didn't bring my boy did you, you wanted to check me out first.
迈克:让人停止呼吸的小手.这种恭维有用吗?
Mike: Breath taking pair of hands, Does that kind of lines really work?
乔治:哦,这都是我们的孩子,你好好查一查吧.
George: Oh from two sons to two pillow, here check out my brude.
迈克:哇,他们都是卢克的兄弟姐妹吗?
Mike: Wow these are all Luke's brothers and sisters?
乔治:是同父异母的兄弟姐妹.别以为我很坏.
George: Half brothers and sisters,
我一直想结婚,但他们的妈妈都对我很好,
don't get me wrong I tried like heck to marry each and everyone of there
哦,上帝啊.
mama's so help me god.
迈克:为什么不结婚?
Mike: What stopped you?
乔治:我总感觉外边,在城市之间有种力量吸引着我.那比生命还要重要.我喜欢风吹在脸颊上的感觉,
George: There is something out there on that stretch of black between
我的心脏向往着太阳.那是一种自由的感觉.我忍不住要撕心裂肺地呼喊出来,因为这种艰苦的生活真是刺激.
city and town
that's bigger than life itself the feel of the wind on your cheeks says your
hearts pumping to the sun drenched extercy of freedom sometimes you just
have to scream
out loud to wonder because it's hurts so good
你知道我在说什么吗?
You know what I'm saying.
迈克:当然了,你连吃冰激凌都这么快.
Mike: Sure I, kinda like when you eat ice cream to fast.
看来,你真的不想有个孩子给你拖后退.
Ah it doesn't really sound like you need a kid to tie you down.
乔治:哦,也许其他小学生们会是个麻烦,
George: Oh maybe these other little puppies might be a problem but Luke's
不过卢克是我第一个儿子,
my first born it's time for him to get out and scratch his name across
是他出去闯一闯,扬名立万的时候了.
the sky.
迈克:听着,你也许没明白.
Mike: Look I don't think you understand,
卢克已经上学了,卢克有自己的朋友.
look Luke's in school now and Luke's got friends.
乔治:我会教给他许多在课堂里根本学不到的本事.
George: I'm going to teach Luke things he can't learn inside four walls
而且他会在这个国家到处交到朋友.
he's going to make friends all over this country.
迈克:我不信.
Mike: I don't know.
乔治:听着,卢克是我儿子.你要不给我带来,我就跟你打官司.我是要定了.
George: Look Luke's is my son either you bring him to me or I get an attorney,
晚上7:30把他带过来,
either way I get him so have me back here by 7:30 tonight and we get to
我们就是好朋友了.
stay buddies.
卢克:嘿,迈克,你去哪里了?
Luke: Hey Mike where were you said you'd be back before lunch.
你说午饭前回来的.嘿,你这是干什么?
Hey what's that all about?
迈克:我只是想抱抱你这个小鬼头.
Mike: I just wanted to give you a hug you little huckle head.
卢克:迈克,如果你是想因为我替你做数学作业而感谢我的话,
Luke: Mike if you trying to thank me for doing your math homework I rather
你还是给我钱吧.
have money.
迈克:嘿,得了吧,难道一个人不能进来抱另一个人吗?你神经太过敏了.
Mike: Hey come on, can't a guy walk in and give another guy a hug
without everybody getting the heebie-jeebies
卢克:不是.
Luke: No.
克莉丝:不…不.
Chrissy: Nooooooo no.
迈克:嘿,嘿,嘿,嘿,怎么了?
Mike: Hey hey hey hey what's the matter?
克莉丝:迈克,老实说,你会穿这身衣服去看电影吗?
Chrissy: Mike be honest will you go to the movies dressed like this?
迈克:不会.你这身衣服会让我很傻的.
Mike: Nope, pettie coats makes me look hippy.
克莉丝:开萝尔非要这样.她让我看起来像小丑.
Chrissy: Carol did this she made me look like a geek.
迈克:哦,想想你还是幸运的呢,你该看看她把本打扮成什么样子过.
Mike: Well hey consider yourself luck you should of seen what she use to do to Ben.
克莉丝:天啊,我该怎么办啊?
Chrissy: Boy am I bummed.
迈克:是的,我也没办法.
Mike: Yea me too.
开萝尔:好了吗,宝贝?
Carol: Ready precious?
迈克:嘿,开萝尔,我需要你的帮助.
Mike: Hey carol I really need your help.
开萝尔:你该知道,长时间以来我一直想听到这样的话"开萝尔,
Carol: Of you only knew how long I've being waiting to hear those words '
我需要你的帮助".我终于听到了,噢…
Carol I need your help' and now that I've heard them plllllllllllll.
迈克:说正经的呢.我一直想联系上妈妈和爸爸,
Mike: Seriously, I'm trying to get a hold of mom and dad and I called
可给旅馆打电话,那里却没有叫西沃的人入住.
the hotel and there is nobody registered under Sever.
开萝尔:你询问姓马龙的人了吗,死脑筋.
Carol: Well did you try under Malone you nahdatrol.
迈克:马龙?开萝尔,开萝尔,
Mike: Malone?Carol Carol.
我要让你看看这是个多么愚蠢的主意.喂,啊,
I'm going to show you want a stupid idea that is ok.
是的,你们那里没有叫麦琪马龙的人入住,
Hello ah yes you don't have anybody there registered under Maggie Malone
是吗?哦,谢谢.
do you?Oh thanks.
开萝尔:迈克,小心眼的女人会觉得有必要说"我说什么来着",
Carol: Mike a lesser woman would feel the need to say I told you so but
但我是个大方的人,我只是想说"噢…"
I'm secure enough for myself merely to say pllllllllllllll.
迈克:嗨,妈妈,天啊,这只是电话留言.
Mike: Hi mom, man it's just the voice mail.
本:卢克说你不对劲,抱抱我,你竟然打扮成这样.
Ben: Luke says your acting weird, hug me and you're wearing bolooni.
迈克:没看见我在打电话吗,你这个小丑.
Mike: Can't you see I'm making a phone call you little geek.Geek.
好的,妈妈,爸爸,哦,
Ok mom, dad ah listen call me back the second you get in Luke's father's
听着,一回来就给我回电话.卢克的父亲来了,但我不知道怎么对付他.
is in town but I just figured out how to deal with him.
迈克:乔治布鲁沃尔,看看你儿子卢克.
Mike: George Bower, meet your son Luke.
乔治:儿子?
George: Son?
本:爸爸.
Ben: Daddy.
迈克:我可以看到你脸上流露出的失望神情.他不是你希望的那样.我们也拿他没办法,我理解,再见.
Mike: I could see the look of disappointment on your face he just not all that you hoped for we're stucked with him I understand, goodbye.
乔治:啊,不,不,他变成一个帅小伙了.
George: Ah no no, he's become a fine strapped young man.
本:很高兴见到你.
Ben: Please to meet you.
乔治:是.真有意思,但你长的不像阿丽莎.
George: Yea, you know it's funny but you don't seem to resemble Alisha.
本:谁?
Ben: Who?
乔治:你妈妈.
George: Your mother.
本:哦,她啊.我总是认为她的名字叫妈妈.
Ben: Oh her, I always just thought her name was mom.
乔治:啊,儿子,你干嘛不坐下来,脱下你的外套,
George: Ah son why don't you just sit down and take of you coat and hat
帽子,耳罩,围巾和手套吧.
and earmuffs and muffler and gloves.
本:不,这里冻死了,我会感冒的.
Ben: No it's nippy in here I can catch a cold.
乔治:听着,你需要改变生活.我要带着你在棉花糖一样的天空下,开车24小时前往南达科他.
George: Look all you need is a change you and me are going to drive
hrs straight under cotton candy skies to South Dakota
本:我喜欢棉花糖.
Ben: Cotton candy give me gas.
乔治:那我们就顶着风到蒙大拿州的冰河地区.那里的空气新鲜,
George: Well then we'll races up the windy road to the glacier of Montana
你可以畅快地呼吸.
where the air is so fresh and crisp you can take a bit out of it.
本:冷空气会让我的鼻子流血.
Ben: Cold air gives me nose bleeds.
乔治:那我们就去亚利桑那,到尘土飞扬的印第安保留区,你可以跟部落里最漂亮的姑娘们跳舞.
George: Well then in Arizona, well kick up some dust on the hopei reservation where the where you can dance with the prettiest maidens of the tribe.
本:跳舞让我…你说姑娘?
Ben: Dancing makes me....maidens you say.
迈克:卢克.
Mike: Luke.
本:呃,那些姑娘多大?
Ben: Like ah how old are these maidens?
迈克:卢克,卢克.
Mike: Luke Luke.
本:哦,我是卢克,你是迈克,你是爸爸
Ben: Oh me Luke, you Mike, you daddy.
迈克:乔治,我们想单独谈谈.
Mike: George will you give us a minute.
乔治:好的.
George: Sure.
迈克:你怎么了?
Mike: What's the matter with you?
本:能不能别打我了?
Ben: Would you quit hitting me.
迈克:能不能别像个大傻瓜似的?
Mike: Would you stop acting like a butt head.
本:能不能闭嘴?
Ben: Why don't you shut up.
迈克:你闭嘴.
Mike: You shut up.
本:不,你闭嘴.
Ben: No you shut up.
迈克:好了,好了,好了,我们要甩点这个家伙.
Mike: Stop it stop it stop it, we've got to get rid of this guy.
本:好.
Ben: Fine.
迈克:好.
Mike: Fine.
本:好.
Ben: Ok.
迈克:好.
Mike: Ok.
乔治:卢克, 跟我走吧,我们一起去兜风,多自由自在啊.
George: So Luke you ready to come with me and spin an 18 wheeler around a culver leaf.
本:我说过了身体不行.实际上,我一坐车就头晕.
Ben: I have motion sickness, in fact, I can't stay with David on the major hurl
乔治:你每天早晨都这样吗?
George: You talk you tight every morning?
本:你说对了.
Ben: Does never body.
乔治:那好吧,直说吧,我知道你怎么想的.
George: Alright, let's cut through the weakness of this sick song.
本:你知道?
Ben and Mike: you do?
乔治:卢克,你要是不想跟我走,那就直说的.
George: Luke if you don't want to come with me just say the word.
本:哦,好吧,这就是我想说的.
Ben: Oh that, yea right that's what I'm up to.
迈克:我也是这个意思.
Mike: And I'm right up there with him.
乔治:哦,也许我来找你就不是个好主意,也许我应该远离你的生活.
George: Well ah maybe this was a bad idea maybe it's easier if I just stayed out of your life.
迈克:是的.
Mike: It is.
本:离远点.
Ben: Much easier.
乔治:好吧,我还是说再见吧.
George: Well I guess this is goodbye then,
你是个体面人,迈克西沃,
you're a decent man Mike Sever I would ask you to take care of Luke of
请你好好照顾卢克,不过别把他宠坏了.
me but it seems like you got that down.
再见,卢克.
Goodbye Luke.
本:哦.
Ben: Oh.
迈克:你要去哪儿?
Mike: Where are you going man?
本:我去要印第安姑娘的地址.
Ben: I want to get the address for that Indian maiden thing.
迈克:你这小子…
Mike: Would you ..
开萝尔:我真不该带你来看什么.
Carol: What was I thinking taking you to see it's raining guts.
克莉丝:我什么也没看到,你老早就把我拖出来了.
Chrissy: I didn't see it you dragged me out early.
开萝尔:都快到结尾了.
Carol: It was almost over.
克莉丝:还没有呢,到那个胖女人爆炸才完呢.
Chrissy: It wasn't over until the fat lady blows up.
本:真难以置信,我成功了.
Ben: I can't believe I pulled it of.
迈克:要不是我在旁边给你打掩护,你早就原形毕露了.
Mike: Ah what do you mean you key most of it every two seconds I'd to yank your foot out of your mouth.
卢克:嘿,你们在干嘛呢?
Luke: Hey guys what's going on?
本和迈克:卢克!
Ben and Mike: Luke!
卢克:你们发什么神经啊.
Luke: You guys need a dog.
迈克:你两个最好的朋友抱你一下还不行吗,你这个傻瓜.
Mike: Can't a couple of your best buddy's give you a hug you little button nose
卢克:去找个傻姑娘吧.
Luke: A big goofy dog.
迈克:妈妈,爸爸,你们终于回来了?
Mike: Mom dad what are you guys doing back?
杰森:我们赶第一个航班回来的,只有这样才能阻止你,
Jason: We grabbed the first flight we could so we could stopped you before
要不你会实施你那愚蠢的计划.
you went ahead with this idiotic plan.
本:告诉你们,一点都不愚蠢.这个计划很奏效.迈克让我干的.
Ben: For your information it was not idiotic it worked like a charm and Mike will take it form here.
麦琪:迈克,你不会真的告诉我,你已经那么去做了吧?
Maggie: Mike did you actually tell me you pulled that hair braid scheme.
迈克:妈妈,
Mike: Mom I had to,
我必须这样.乔治布鲁沃尔是个开卡车的主儿,
I mean George Bower is a truck driving flake and he was threatening to
他威胁打官司要回卢克.
go to court to take Luke.
杰森:迈克,卢克15岁了.
Jason: Mike, Luke is 15 years old if he tells the judge he doesn't want
如果卢克对法官说不想跟他爸爸走,他也毫无办法.
to go he will be listened to.
迈克:但爸爸,这并不是我做这件事的唯一理由.卢克认为他爸爸是个秘密特工才抛弃他的.
Mike: But dad that wasn't the only reason that I did this, I mean Luke think that his dad left he because he was some kind of secret agent.
杰森:卢克这样被抛弃的孩子编造这样的故事只是为了让自己心里好受点.
Jason: Abandon kids make up all kinds of stories to keep from feeling they weren't wanted.
迈克:你是说卢克编造了这一切吗?
Mike: You mean you think Luke made this up?
杰森:时间一长,连他自己都相信了.
Jason: A long time ago and somewhere along the line he started to believe it.
迈克:不过爸爸,他见了爸爸一切就都露馅了.
Mike: But dad if he meets his father he's going to find out the truth.
杰森:这会让他伤心的.但彻底了解自己的父亲是对他将来的成长具有很重要的意义.
Jason: And that may hurt Mike but facing the truth about his father is an important part of his growing up.
迈克:那好吧.对不起我把事情弄砸了.不过爸爸,我不想失去卢克.
Mike: Ok alright, I'm sorry I screwed up but dad I don't want to loss Luke .
麦琪:我们都和你一样,但最终还得他自己来决定.
Maggie: Well none of us does Mike but staying has to be his decision.
杰森:你该去跟卢克说,今天就是现在,
Jason: You owe it to Luke to tell him that he can meet his dad right
他可去见自己的爸爸.
now today.
迈克:好吧,我去告诉他.
Mike: Ok fine I'll tell him.
不过,是我把卢克带进我们家的,
But I brought Luke into this house and if he's leaving I want to be the
如果他真要离开,还得由我送他走.
one to see him of.
卢克:到底发生什么事了,我知道不是去看尼克斯篮球队的比赛.
Luke: So what's going on I know we're not going to the Nicks game.
迈克:哦,好吧,你怎么知道我们不是呢?
Mike: Oh yea and how did you figure that one out.
卢克:很简单,他们在犹他州打客场比赛呢.
Luke: Well for one thing the games sold out for another it's in Utah.
迈克:好吧,卢克,我要带你去曼哈顿.
Mike: Ok Luke listen I'm taking you to Manhattan,
如果不想去,你可以不去.但你父亲在那里.
you don't have to go if you don't want to but your father's there.
卢克:我爸爸,我爸爸来了?
Luke: My dad, my dad's here?
迈克:是的.儿童福利局的人找到了他,他们又找到了.我上午去看他了.
Mike: Yea, you see the bureau of child welfare traced him down and they got a hold of me, I saw him this morning.
卢克:你见他了,那为什么不告诉我?
Luke: You saw him why didn't you tell me?
迈克:我很抱歉没告诉你.我是说,你的亲人是他,不是我.但我把你当亲人看待,卢克.
Mike: I know and I'm sorry I should of, I mean he's your family and I'm not but I feel like your family Luke.
卢克:他是一个什么样的人?
Luke: So what kind of guy is he?
迈克:哦,他很友好,很潇洒,他走过很多地方.
Mike: Well ah, he's friendly, colorful, he's well traveled.
卢克:那他知道我们去看他吗,他看到我会惊讶吗?
Luke: Does he know we're coming is he going to be surprise to see me?
迈克:哦,是的.
Mike: Oh yea.
乔治:嗨,卢克.
George: Hi Luke.
卢克:嗨.
Luke: Hi
乔治:坐吧.
George: Let's sit down.
卢克:好的.
Luke: Alright
乔治:你跟阿丽莎长的很像.
George: You look just like Alisha.
卢克:是的,跟你也很像.你一紧张也用大拇指敲桌子.
Luke: Yea I know, I look like you too.You tap your thumb when you're nervous
乔治:这是我们家的遗传.嘿,你长了一对布鲁沃尔家的眉毛,
George: it runs in the family, hey you got the Bower eyebrows,
你能这样吗?还要厉害,太棒了.
can you do this?Even better that's great
卢克:我知道这件事应该是个大秘密.
Luke: I know this is supposed to be top secret and everything but could
但你能告诉我当初为什么离开我和妈妈.
you tell me why you had to leave mom and me?
乔治:这不是秘密.我只是个大孩子,
George: No secret, I was just a big kid and scared to death,
害怕的要命.
how could I take care of either one of you I could hardly take care of
我照顾不了你们娘俩.我连自己都养活了不了.
myself.
卢克:不说了.我知道你是个特工什么的.
Luke: It's ok I know you are a secret agent or something.
乔治:这个想法是从哪里来的?
George: Where did you get an idea like that?
卢克:我不知道,我只是这么想的.
Luke: Well I don't know I just sort of figured it out.
乔治:你想错了.我只是个干粗活的,
George: Well you figured it wrong I was just a snot nose kid with a played
整天开着个破卡车到处跑,风吹日晒的.
out 8 track of the Osborn brother's catching sunlight on my dash broad.
卢克:你离开我们没有理由,只是离开这么简单吗?
Luke: There was no reason you just left because you felt like it?
乔治:哦,忘了吧,事情都过去了.
George: Oh come on son what's passed is passed.
卢克:这些日子,我一直以为你去干大事了,
Luke: All this time I though you were saving the country,
没想到你只是逃跑了.
you were just running away
乔治:嘿,我回来就是要弥补过去的.
George: hey I came back to make it up to you come with me,
跟着我吧,你已经长大了,不再是我的累赘了.
you're old enough to ride right here in my hip pocket without slowing me down,
我们俩,去各个城市,进各种酒吧,到处游逛,像亲密的朋友.
you and me town to town bar to bar in and out of space like a couple of compadres.
亲密朋友?
Luke: Compadres.
乔治:嘿,一个人开车太寂寞了.
George: Hey kido it's down right awesome on the road we can kick some
两个人就好多了,可以互相解解闷,做点开心的事.
butt make some names make the country red.
卢克:要是原来我会很高兴地跟你走.可是现在我不愿意了.
Luke: There was a time really would of jumped at that ,
我在街头流浪了三年.
let me just fill you in on something,
在垃圾桶里找吃的一天到晚怕的要命.最难过的是一到晚上,
I was on the street for 3 years eating out of a dumpster and scared to
我就祈祷,
death I'd get bet up or worst every night I hoped and I prayed that you
盼着你来找我,你能找到我.
were looking for me that you were going to find me.
乔治:我来了.
George: Here I am.
卢克:你来的太迟了.是迈克发现了我,
Luke: You're too late,
是迈克给了我一个家,
Mike was the one who found me Mike put a roof over my head Mike put
是迈克把我抱在怀里对我说我很聪明,让我读书.
his arm around me and told me that I was smart and told me
他是我的亲人.
that it was ok to care he gave me a family.
乔治:我是你的亲人,所以我才来找你.
George: I'm your family that's why I traced you down.
卢克:不,你不是.
Luke: No you didn't,
是儿童福利局找到你的.如果没有,
the bureau of child welfare had to trace you down if they hadn't you'd
鬼才知道你躲在哪里呢,根本没心思想我.
still be god knows where not giving a damn about me.
乔治:我自己有一套关心你的方式.
George: I care about you the only way I know how,
我在卡车里给你留了一个座,给你留了一份三明治.
I got a spare sit and an extra sandwich in the glove compartment I want
我想让你就坐到我的身边.
you right there beside me,
怎么样?
what do you say?
迈克:嘿,卢克,谈的怎么样?
卢克:嘿,管别人呢,一个男人不能拥抱另一个男人吗?走吧,迈克,我们回家.
00:22:29,000
Mike: Hey Luke what's going on? Luke: Hey can't a guy give another guy a hug without anyone getting the heebie-jeebies?Come on Mike let's go home.